Craig Seymour Collection, 1968-2006 SC 144
Archives of African American Music and Culture
Craig Seymour Collection
1968-2006
Archives of African American Music and Culture
Seymour, Craig
SC 144
7 document cases 2.94 linear feet
126 Audiocassettes
1 microcassette
1 Audio Disc CD
36 Audio Discs CD-R
The collection consists of articles, clippings, and interviews compiled during research for Seymour's book, Luther: The Life and Longing of Luther Vandross (2004), and subsequent research on topics related to R&B musicians, black music genres, the black gay community and gay musicians. Also included are audiocassettes containing interviews conducted by Seymour with Luther Vandross, various R&B musicians and record company personnel, as well as a large collection of mixtapes and commercial CDs.
Arrangement
Arranged in six series:
Series 1: Luther Vandross research files (chronological)
Series 2: Artist clippings
Series 3: Subject files
Series 4: Interviews
Series 5: Mixtapes and miscellaneous media
Series 6: Magazines
Biographical / Historical
Author, photographer, and academic Craig Seymour holds a Ph.D from University of Maryland at College Park, is Associate Professor of Journalism at Northern Illinois University, and has taught writing at the University of Massachusetts at Dartmouth. He has written two books, the memoir All I Could Bare: My Life in the Strip Clubs of Gay Washington, D.C. and a biography of Luther Vandross, Luther: The Life and Longing of Luther Vandross. The materials in this collection pertain to Seymour's book on Vandross and include materials he used to research this book, including articles, interviews, clippings, and mixtapes.
Access Restrictions
Use of time-based media materials (audio and video) may require production of listening or viewing copies.
Access to streaming audio, moving image, and full resolution digital image materials may currently be restricted to researchers who can authenticate with an IU account or who are physically present on campus. Remote streaming to individual researchers may be allowed with the completion of applicable forms.
For further information about access to online audiovisual materials, contact AAAMC staff at aaamc@indiana.edu.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Craig Seymour in 2008.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of articles, clippings, and interviews compiled during research for Seymour's book, Luther: The Life and Longing of Luther Vandross (2004). The collection is divided into six series. Series 1 includes files, arranged chronologically, pertaining specifically to Luther Vandross. Materials include press clippings and releases, articles, and programs. Series 2 includes articles, press clippings, and notes about various artists, arranged in alphabetical order. Many of these artists are referenced in the Vandross biography. Series 3 includes subject files, primarily about various black music genres, arranged alphabetically. Some files also reference the black gay community and gay musicians. Series 4 includes audiocassettes containing interviews conducted by Seymour [and others?] with Luther Vandross, various R&B musicians and record company personnel, and about black gay culture and discrimination.
Rhythm and blues musicians; African American singers -- Biography; Vandross, Luther
- 1. Luther Vandross research files (chronological)
  - Clippings and press release, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Johnson, Herschel, "The Secret World of Studio Music," Black Enterprise, pp. 72-74, 1981-12 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "The Man Most Likely…," Blues & Soul & Disco Music Review, 1981-11-03 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Gardner, Mike, "Luther--The Ladies Session Man," Record Mirror, p. 29, 1982-11-27 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Elms, Robert, "Soul For Hire," The Face, pp. 46-47, 1982-11 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Adler, Bill, "Song," People, pp. 101-102, 1983-02-28 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "New Voices of the Eighties," Ebony, pp. 58-59, 1983-03 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Clippings + notes, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Norment, Lynn, "Luther Vandross: The Voice That Seduces Millions," Ebony, pp. 83-85, 88, 1985-12 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Nathan, David, "Luther Vandross: The Complete Soul Man!," Blues & Soul, pp. 16-18 (2 copies), 1986-12-02-1986-12-15 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Harrington, Richard, "Luther Vandross, Soul & Body," Washington Post, 1986-04-06 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Luther The Heat Is On!," Blues & Soul, pp. 10-11, 1988-10-25 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Clippings + Oprah Winfrey Show Transcripts (11/8 & 3/6), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Nathan, David, "Luther The Leader of the Pack," Blues & Soul, pp. 10-11, 1989-04-04-1989-04-17 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Clippings + Oprah Winfrey Show transcript (6/27), 1990 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Clippings, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Norment, Lynn, "Love Power!," Ebony, pp. 93-98 (2 photocopies), 1991-12 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Hoerburger, Rob, "Mr. Love's Lament," The New York Times Magazine, pp. 53, 58, 60, 63, 1991-09-22 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Cooper, Mark, "Battle of the Bulge," Q, pp. 56-58, 1991-08 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Pond, Steve, "Luther Hears a Whoo!," Us, pp. 73-74, 1991-09 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Clippings, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Rogers, Charles E., "Luther: The Man, The Music, The Controversy," Black Elegance, pp. 42-44, 86, 1994-11-1994-12 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Boyd, Herb, "If Luther's Music Be the Food of Life…," Class, pp. 26-28, 1994-10-1994-11 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Luther Vandross In A Class By Himself," EM, pp. 65-66, 1994-12 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Flanagan, Sylvia P., "Luther Vandross Tells Why He Recorded Remakes on New Album," Jet, pp. 36-39, 1994-10-24 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Clippings + Oprah transcript (12/21), 1995 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Clippings, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Clippings + Your Secret Love Tour Itinerary, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Clippings + Oprah Winfrey Show transcripts (8/31 & 11/13), 1998 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - "Soul Survivor," People, pp. 121-124, 1998-09-07 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Clippings, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Georgiades, William, "Luther Gets Lean," Us Weekly, pp. 66-67, 2001-06-18 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Interview with Jamie Brown, Sister2Sister, pp. 38-53, 2001-10 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Clippings, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Sinclair, Tom, "Lost Soul," Entertainment Weekly, pp. 35-37, 2003-11-17 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Smolowe, Jill, "Luther Sings Again," People, pp. 95-96, 2003-11-20 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Spera, Keith, "The Essence of Luther," The Times Picayune, pp. 21-23, 2003-07-04 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Clippings, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Waldron, Clarence, "Luther Vandross: In 'good spirits' as he continues to recover from last year's stroke," Jet, pp. 58-63, 2004-01-19 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Clippings, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Dagostino, Mark and Michelle Tauber, "1951-2005 Remembering Luther," People, pp. 80-84, 2005-07-18 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Dedication issue of Jet, 2005-07-25 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - R/L/S - Notes about interview questions, possibly intended for Vandross, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Transcript of Craig Seymour's Luther: The Life and Longing of Luther Vandross, circa 2000 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- 2. Artist clippings
  - Adams, Patrick, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Tribute + notes
  - Arbus, Diane, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Bosworth, Patricia, "Illusions of Arbus," Vanity Fair, pp. 152-157, 186-188
  - Arrested Development, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Atlanta Journal and Constitution
  - Austin, Dallas, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Clippings
  - Badu, Erykah, 1997-2000 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    3 articles: A) Iannacci, Elio, "Believing in Baduizm," Icon, p. 53. May 1997. B) King, Jason, "When Autobiography Becomes Soul: Erykah Badu and the Cultural Politics of Black Feminism," Women & Performance: A Journal of Feminist Theory, Issue 19, 10:1-2, 1999. C) Watson, Margeaux, "Mama's Got a Brand-New Bag," Time Out New York, p. 32, Oct. 16-23, 2000. Also includes complete issue of Essence, August 1997.
  - Blige, Mary J., 1999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    2 articles: A) "Mary J. Blige Tells Why Dropping Out of High School Was A Big Mistake," Jet, pp.59-62, Nov. 29, 1999. B) Powers, Ann, "Dear Superstar: Mary J. Blige," Blender, pp. 56-59 [unknown date]
  - Blige, Mary J., 1992-2006 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Blige, Mary J., 1995-1998 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Newspaper clippings
  - Braxton, Toni, 1993-2002 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Brown, Foxy, 1996-1999 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    10 articles: A) Colon, Susan, "Have Yourself A Foxy Little New Year," Jane, pp. 136-137, Jan./Feb. 1999. B) "Foxy Meets Cyndi," Interview, pp. 111-114, May 1997. C) Gonzales, Michael A., "Mack Divas," The Source, pp. 62-64, Feb. 1997. D) Hilton, Als, "Touch Me Tease Me," Bazaar, pp. 97-99, 127, 131, July 1997. E) Osorio, Kim, "Chocolate Girl Wonder," The Source, pp. 137-140, Jan. 1999. F) Smith, Danyel, "Foxy Brown is the Illest," Vibe, pp. 113-116, Dec. 1998-Jan. 1999. G) Stovall, Natasha, "Foxy Lady," Spin, p. 44, Dec. 1996. H) Suares, Carl Keenan, "Foxy Lady," Beat-Down, pp. 29-30 [uknown date]. I) "The Firm: The Takeover Begins," The Source, pp. 162-166, 214, Dec. 1997. J) Toure, "Foxy Brown," Rolling Stone, p. 74, Dec. 24, 1998-Jan. 7, 1999.
  - Brown, Foxy, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Brown, Jocelyn, 2001-2003 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Cara, Irene, 1975-2001 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Carey, Mariah, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Clippings + notes + photocopied article. Seymour, Craig, "On the Bright Track," The Washington Post, Section G, Nov. 14, 1999
  - Carey, Mariah, 1999-11-14 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Original newspaper article. Seymour, Craig, "On the Bright Track," The Washington Post, Section G
  - Change, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Clippings + notes
  - Cherry, Neneh, 1992-12-08 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Newspaper article. Smith, RJ, "Feel Like Going Home," Voice, p. 73
  - Chic, 1979-1992 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Clinton, George, 1978-1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Clinton, George, 1993-11-02 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Newspaper article. Christgau, Robert, "Loose Canon," Voice, p. 94
  - Cobbs, Michelle, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Cole, David, 1995-1999 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Cole, David, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Newspaper article. Cooper, Carol, "David Cole, 1963-1995," Voice, p. 68
  - Cooke, Sam, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Creed, Linda, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Crow, Sheryl, 2006-08 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    DiGiacomo, Frank, "A Rock of Her Own," Vanity Fair, pp. 144-150, 188
  - Dahl, Steve, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Dame, Deah, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Destiny's Child, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Frere-Jones, Sasha, "Do You Believe in Destiny?," Blender, pp. 52-57
  - Donnie, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Roni Sarig article
  - DJ Screw, 2001-04 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Photocopied article. Hall, Michael, "The Slow Life and Fast Death of DJ Screw," Texas Monthly, pp. 93-161
  - Dupri, Jermaine, 1992-2004 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Clippings + article. Rosen, Jody, "The Hitman," Blender, pp. 96-100 [date unknown]
  - Elliott, Missy (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Hirshey, Gerri, "Rhymes & Misdemeanors," Rolling Stone, pp. 54-57, 166
  - Evans, Faith, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Herman, James Patrick, "True Faith," pp. 332-338
  - Flack, Roberta, 1971-2002 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Clippings + notes + article. Roberta Flack and Alicia Keys discuss music. "Simply the Best," Essence, pp. 112-118, 170, March 2002.
  - Franklin, Aretha, 1968-1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Photocopied magazine clippings
  - Franklin, Carolyn, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Garfield, Wayne, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Notes
  - Gaye, Marvin, 1984-2001 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Guthrie, Gwen, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Hardy, James Earl, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    E-mail correspondence
  - Hathaway, Donny, 1971-1979 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Houston, Whitney, 1993-2006 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    13 clippings + articles: A) Ammons, Kevin and Nancy Bacon, "Whitney's Gay Galpal Bitter Love Triangle," The National Enquirer, pp. 38-39, Oct. 15, 1996. B) Bowman, Jeffery, Excerpt from DIVA: The Totally Un-authorized Biography of Whitney Houston, "Woman Who Broke Whitney Houston's Heart," Star, pp. 18-19, Nov. 1, 1994. C) Galvin, Peter, "Whitney & Cece Each Other's Emotional Bodyguards," Interview, pp. 94-96, February 1995. D) Gentile, Don, "Crack Turned Whitney Into A Sex-Crazed Monster," The National Enquirer, pp. 20-23, April 17, 2006. E) Gentile, Don, John South, and Reginald Fitz, "Whitney Facing Death," The National Enquirer, pp. 32-33, June 6, 2000. F) Hirschberg, Lynn, "Thoroughly Modern Whitney," Vanity Fair, pp. 240-243, 272-276, Nov. 1992. G) Jones, James T. IV, "Whitney's Voice Triumphs Over All," USA Today, July 13, 1993. H) LaFontaine, Dave, "Whitney's Nightmare Comeback," Star, pp. 2-3, Aug. 30, 1994. I) South, John, "Whitney Houston's Father Offered Me $6,000 To Break Her Lesbian Pal's Legs," The National Enquirer, p. 5, April 11, 1995. J) South, John and Patricia Shipp, "Whitney Tragedy," The National Enquirer, pp. 10-11, Jan. 16, 2006. K) Walters, Barry, "She Will Always Love You," Out, pp. 53-59, 113, 117, May 2000. L) "What Bizarre Behavior!," Globe, pp. 4-5, March 27, 2001. Also includes complete issue of Entertainment Weekly, February 5, 1993.
  - Hyman, Phyllis, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Newspaper clippings + article. Hardy, James Earl, "The Goddess of Love Speaks," Alternatives, pp. 19-21
  - India Arie, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Jackson, Janet, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Divorce and lawsuits clippings
  - Jackson, Janet, 1991-2004 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Miscellaneous clippings
  - Jackson, Janet, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    5 newspaper articles: A) Brown, Georgia, "Out of Character," Voice, p. 55, July 27, 1993. B) Christgau, Robert, "Making A Spectacle of Herself," Voice, p. 69-70, Jan. 4, 1994. C) Coleman, Beth, "Justice Is a Lady," Voice, p. 64, Aug. 3, 1993. D) Jones, James T. IV, "Career Soars On Wings of Desire," USA Today, D1, May 3, 1993. E) Jones, James T. IV, "Sexy 'janet.' Reveals A Grown-Up Jackson," USA Today, D1, May 18, 1993.
  - Jackson, Janet, 1990-2006 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    45 articles: A) Carney, Thomas, "Architectural Digest Visits Janet Jackson," Architectural Digest, pp. 135-139, March 1998. B) (2 copies) Chambers, Veronica, "Janet Jackson On Her Secret Marriage, Divorce, and Living Happily Ever After," Honey, pp. 56-61, Aug. 2000. C) Christian, Margena A., "Janet Fine & Fabulous At 40!," Jet, pp. 60-65, June 5, 2006. D) Colon, Suzan, "Welcome to Planet Janet," Jane, pp. 89-92, Oct. 1998. E) DeCurtis, Anthony, "Free At Last," Rolling Stone, pp. 41-44, 70, Feb. 22, 1990. F) (2 copies) Gordinier, Jeff, "Will the Real Janet Jackson Please Stand Up?," Entertainment Weekly, pp. 36-39, May 4, 2001. G) (2 copies) Higginbotham, Adam, "Sex and the Single Woman," Blender, pp. 90-98. H) Holden, Angela, "Janet Hollywood," Sky International, pp. 6-12, June 1993. I) Holley, Jon-Andre, "Janet Jackson Indiana Rope Trick," Blues & Soul, Oct. 21-Nov. 3, 1997. J) Holz, Geroge, "Planet Janet," Us, pp. 68-69, 73-74, 92, Aug. 1993. K) Jackson, Janet, "Tina Turner," Rolling Stone, p. 66, April 21, 2005. L) "Janet Jackson," Essence, June 2004. M) (2 copies) Johnson, Pamela, "Janet On Janet," Essence, pp. 74-76, Jan. 1996. N) Johnson, Pamela, "Janet Jackson Through Thick and Thin," Essence, pp. 115-116, 202, 204, May 1998. O) (2 copies) Johnson, Robert E., "Janet Jackson," Jet, pp. 58-62, Dec. 27-Jan. 3, 1994. P) Keeps, David, "Janet Unzipped," The Face, pp. 122-126, 196. Q) McClellan, Jim, "Staying Alive," Arena, pp. 78-85, Dec. 1997. R) (2 copies) Norment, Lynn, "Grown-up Janet Jackson Talks About Racism, Sensuality, and the Whole Jackson Family," Ebony, pp. 36-38, 40, 42, Sept. 1993. S) (2 copies) Norment, Lynn, "Janet," Ebony, pp. 148-153, April 2004. T) Pond, Steve, "Janet," Us, pp. 42-49, 122, Nov. 1995. U) (2 copies) Randolph, Laura B., "Janet," Ebony, pp. 156-158, 160-162, Dec. 1997. V) Ritz, David, "Design of a Decade," W) Ritz, David, "I Janet," Essence, pp. 137-138, 198, Sept. 2001. X) (2 copies) Ritz, David, "Janet's Passions," Essence, pp. 84-86, 140, 142, May 1993. Y) Ritz, David, "Sex, Sadness, & The Triumph of Janet Jackson," Rolling Stone, pp. 39-45, Oct. 1, 1998. Z) Ritz, David, "Sexual Healing," Rolling Stone, pp. 38-43, 82, Sept. 16, 1993. AA) (2 copies) Samuels, Allison, "Rhythm and the Blues," Newsweek, Nov. 17, 1997. AB) Seymour, Craig, "Living Single," Vibe, pp. 97-101, May 2001. AC) (2 copies) Shaw, Jessica, "All For Her," Shape, pp. 58-63, 2001. AD) Smith, Danyel, "Janet's Back," Vibe, pp. 85-90, Nov. 1997. AE) Smith, Danyel, "Working Girl," Vibe, pp. 49-52, 130, 133, Oct. 1994. AF) Sweeney, Hillary, "Stunning Star Janet Sexy," Star, pp. 6-7, April 26, 1994. AG) (2 copies) Tannenbaum, Rob, "America's Most Wanted," Blender, pp. 118-128, June/July 2004.
  - Jackson, Michael, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    14 clippings + articles: A) (7 copies) French, Alex, "Jackson Jive," The New Haven Advocate, pp. 14-17, Sept. 30, 2004. B) (7 copies) Vinciguerra, Thomas, "If You Knew Michael Like We Knew Michael," The New York Times, p. 7, Oct. 24, 2004.
  - Jackson, Millie, 1981-2004 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Jaheim, 2002-2006 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Jones, Jill, 1987-07-11 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Wilde, John, "Cerebral Tease," Melody Maker, p. 10-11
  - Khan, Chaka, 1980-1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Clippings + notes + article. "Chaka is 'Naughty' But Nice," Jet, pp. 60-62, Aug. 14, 1980.
  - Khan, Chaka, 1979-1997 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    4 newspaper articles: A) Kelly, Danny, "The Dreams of an Everyday Housewife," New Musical Express, pp. 6-7, Dec. 1, 1984. B) McLellan, Joseph, "The Divine And Sassy Sarah," The Washington Post, April 5, 1990. C) Roeser, Steve, "Through The Fire, To The Limit," Goldmine, pp. 16-20, 122, 124, 126, 156, Jan. 31, 1997. D) Schruers, Fred, "Chaka Khan, Earth Mother," Rolling Stone, pp. 18-20, April 5, 1979.
  - Knuckles, Frankie, 1992-08-18 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Flick, Larry, "Spin Doctor," The Advocate, pp. 74-75
  - Labelle, 1975-1992 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    6 clippings + notes + articles: A) Alexander, Yale, "Ring My Labelle," NYQ, Dec. 15, 1991. B) Ebert, Alan, "After 16 Years a Trio Breaks Up. Labelle, A Whodunit," Essence, pp. 73-76, 79-87, Feb. 1976. C) Harris, Art, Rolling Stone, pp. 42-46, July 3, 1975. D) Laermer, Richard, "Nona Hendryx, Both Sides Now," The Advocate, pp. 58-60, Feb. 11, 1992. E) Sanders, Charles L., "Patti Labelle: On Her Own And Doing Great," Ebony, pp. 162-167, Sept. 1978. F) Weston, Martin, "Labelle," Ebony, pp. 100-109, May 1976.
  - Labelle, Patti, 1990-2002 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Clippings + notes + newspaper clips
  - Lasley, David, 1999-2003 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Lee, Laura, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Levan, Larry, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Lil Jon, 2004-2005 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    3 clippings + articles: A) Hall, Rashaun, "Lil Jon Is Juiced For new Release," Billboard Upfront, Nov. 12, 2004. B) Endelman, Michael, "Three Days in the Crunk Factory," Entertainment Weekly, pp. 69-73, Sept. 24, 2004. C) Alvarez, Gabriel, "Yes Dem to Death," XXL, pp. 100-108, 178, July 2004.
  - Lil Wayne, 2005-11 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Rubin, Peter, "Love My Style," XXL Magazine, pp. 104-106, 110
  - Long, Peter, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Lopes, Lisa "Left Eye", 1996-2005 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    4 clippings + articles: A) Brown, Jamie Foster, "Funeral For A Superstar," Sister2Sister, pp. 44-54, July 2002. B) Brown, Jamie Foster, "Lisa 'Left Eye' Lopes: Left Eye Blasts TLC," Sister2Sister, pp. 34-45, Jan. 2000. C) Brown, Jamie Foster, "TLC's Lisa 'Left Eye' Lopes," Sister2Sister, pp. 24-41, Feb. 1998. D) Harding, Quaneza Laveda, "Who are you, Black man? Tell us!!!!!: Lisa "Left Eye" Lopes and Andre Rison," Sister2Sister, pp. 64-67, Sept. 1996.
  - Lynn, Cheryl, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Madonna, 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    10 newspaper clippings + newspaper articles: A) Brown, Joe, "Madonna Tour in Vogue," Voice, [date unknown]. B) Brown, Patricia Leigh, "Video and Theater Shape a New Madonna," The New York Times, p. 8, June 17, 1990. C) Christgau, Robert, "Madonnathinking Madonnabout Madonnamusic," Voice, pp. 31-33, May 28, 1991. D) Harrington, Richard, "Madonna of the Multimedia," The Washington Post, G1, [date unknown]. E) Holden, Stephen, "Madonna Re-Creates Herself—Again," The New York Times, pp. 1, 12, March 19, 1989. F) Pareles, Jon, "Madonna Saunters Down Tin Pan Alley," The New York Times, p. 27, May 20, 1990. G) Udovitch, Mim, "Beyond Ambition," Voice, Dec. 11, 1990. H) Udovitch, Mim, "Like A Superstar," Voice, p. 83, June 12, 1990. I) Udovitch, Mim, "Satirical Girl; Unlucky Star: Madonna gets Browned out," Voice, [date unknown]. J) Waxman, Sharon, "The Roots of Madonna," The Washington Post, R1, May 14, 1991.
  - Mardin, Arif, 1986-2001 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Mathis, Johnny, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Clipping + article. Green, Jesse, "Forever Johnny," The New Yorker, pp. 54-61, July 3, 2000.
  - MC Lyte, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Mills, Stephanie, 1982-02 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Sanders, Charles L., "Stephanie Mills," Ebony, pp. 36-38, 40, 44
  - Monica, 1998-2002 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    24 articles: A) Amodio, Rosie, "Monica Uncensored!," YM, pp. 76-78, Nov. 1998. B) Bernard, April P., "The 21 Hottest Stars Under 21," Teen People, p. 54, June/July 1999. C) Brown, Jamie Foster, "Monica: Her Tragedy, Laughter, Sadness, and Warmth,", Sister2Sister, pp. 52-67, Sept. 2002. D) Checkoway, Laura, "Through The Fire," Vibe, pp. 106-109. E) Daum, Meghan, "Fresh Starts," In Style, pp. 18, 139-143, Jan. 1999. F) (2 copies) Gardner, Elysa, "Next From the Diva Machine," Los Angeles Times, July 7, 1998. G) Graham, Jennifer, "Modern Monica," TV Guide, p. 8, Dec. 2, 2000. H) Gregory, Deborah, "Monica: At Sweet 17, She's Back With A Sophomore Album," Essence, p. 84, Oct. 1998. I) Hanrhan, Michael, "Pop Star Monica Watches in Horror as Live-In Love Kills Himself," National Enquirer, pp. 8-9, Aug. 15, 2000. J) (3 copies) Johnson, Ethel M., "Better Days," Upscale, pp. 67-69, June/July 2002. K) Louie, Rebecca, "Miss Thang," Vibe, p. 68. L) M., Rudi, "All Eyez On Monica," Black Beat, pp. 13-17, Nov. 2002. M) "Monica: Back and Better Than Ever," Black Diaspora, pp. 16-18, 35, July/Aug. 2002. N) "Monica Proves She Has Staying Power With Hit Album, 'The Boy Is Mine'," Jet, pp. 60-65, July 19, 1999. O) "Monica's Movie Diary," YM, pp. 78-79, Jan. 2001. P) Murray, Jawn, "Monica: All Eyez On Her," Black Elegance, pp. 40-43. Q) Myricks, Daneesa, "Monica: New Look, New Sound," Elite Black Hair, Styles N' Trends, pp. 68-70, Sept. 2002. R) Royer, Jessica, "Three Times A Lady," Sophisticate's Black Hair. S) Seymour, Craig, "Pain is Love," Vibe, pp. 133-135. T) Stagg, Ellen, "Welcome to Atlanta," Flaunt, Aug. 2002. U) Summers, Gerrie E., Hype Hair, p. 61, Aug. 2002.
  - Monica, 1998-2002 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Clippings + notes + newspaper article. Seymour, Craig, "The Boy Is Whose?," Village Voice, p. 109, Aug. 4, 1998.
  - Nesby, Ann, 1996-2002 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Ninja, Willi, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Notorious B.I.G., 1998-01 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Aaron, Charles, "The Notorious B.I.G.," Spin, pp. 58-63 + e-mail clippings
  - Notorious B.I.G., 1998 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Outkast, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 3)